我在圣所看到马吉了
I saw Makee on Sanctuary.
－马吉死了－我知道
- Makee's dead. - I know.
我亲手杀的她
I shot her myself.
你对圣所事件的描述
Your account of events on Sanctuary
令人怀疑
has proven dubious.
我知道你们这帮混蛋怎么想的 我曾经也是你
I know how you assholes think. I was you once.
还有其他事可以做 其他的方式活下去
There's other things to be, other ways to live.
不许放弃
Don't you quit.
起来
Get up.
我知道凯瑟琳·哈尔西在哪
I know the location of Catherine Halsey.
对你来说不是钱的问题 对不对
It's not about the money for you, is it?
是她对你做了什么
It's about what she did to ya.
索伦绝不会丢下你们任何一个人
Soren never would've left any of you behind.
你被捕了
You're under arrest.
鲁比·安买下了索伦的船员
Ruby Ann bought Soren's crew.
等我爸回来 他就会保护我们
When my dad comes back, he'll protect us.
他回不来了
He's not coming back!
我想给你介绍个人
I want to introduce you to someone.
这位是朱莉娅 她将是你的随从
This is Julia. She'll be your attendant.
她在哪儿
Where is she?
科塔娜  她很安全
Cortana, she's secure.
我给你的问题有什么进展吗
Have you made any progress with the problem I gave you?
不管采取什么行动
All of my simulations returned the same result,
我所有模拟结果都是一样的
regardless of any action taken.
所以没什么可做的了
So there's nothing to be done.
我当时在扫描波段
I was scanning the band,
然后就听到了干扰中有声音
and I heard something in the interference.
你听到了一段信息
You heard a message.
这种情况还会再次发生
This will happen again.
我希望你去寻找
I want you to post your evidence
星盟其他活动的证据
of the Covenant's other activities.
按下按钮 我就会来找你
Press the button, and I'll find you.
新来的这人 让我们护送一个技术团队
This new guy, he's got us escorting a tech team
执行什么修复任务
on some fix-it mission.
如果你要派钴队去另个通讯中继站
If you're sending Cobalt to another comms array,
最好告诉他们可能会碰到星盟
you better tell them to expect the Covenant.
我不会授权银队
I cannot authorize Silver Team
执行战斗任务
to perform combat operations.
－我们可以作战了吗－是的
- We're cleared for combat? - Affirmative.
任务具体内容是什么
What exactly is the mission?
在致远星的星盟
The Covenant's on Reach.
还有七公里到达目的地
Seven clicks to target.
里兹
Riz?
钴队三号 R队 这里是银队三号结束
Cobalt Three, Romeo, this is Silver Three, over.
钴队队员 这里是银队三号
Any Cobalt element, this is Silver Three.
我们正前往你处 收到了吗
We are en route to your position, how copy?
试下中继站
Try the relay.
韦谢格勒中继站 这里是银队三号
Visegrád Relay, this is Silver Three.
检查无线信号 完毕
Radio check, over.
有空中支援吗
We getting air support for this?
韦谢格勒中继站 这里是银队三号
Visegrád Relay, this is Silver Three.
其他人呢
Where is everybody?
－完毕－就我们自己
- Over. - We're on our own.
舰队指挥部不相信致远星上有星盟
FLEETCOM doesn't believe the Covenant's on Reach.
他们只认为钴队不见了而已
They just think Cobalt's missing.
这次是搜救任务
This is a search and rescue mission,
但我们要考虑到钴队可能
but we need to be prepared for the possibility
遇到什么东西了
that Cobalt ran into something.
星盟吗
Something Covenant?
指挥部认为这个星球对方过不来
Command thinks this planet's untouchable.
他们没看到我们所看到的
They haven't seen what we've seen,
所以不如我们了解情况
and they don't know what we know.
我这么说吧 我们会不可避免地遇上他们
I'll tell you this, we will have contact.
那之前 就只有我们
Until then, it's just us.
你觉得这样合适吗
This seem right to you?
看看能不能恢复电力
See if you can get the power up.
收到 士官长
Copy, Chief.
走的时候很匆忙
Left in a hurry.
没有钴队踪迹 也没有破坏的痕迹
No sign of Cobalt, no breach marks at the--
刚什么动静
What the hell was that?
不清楚 从没听过
I don't know, I've never heard anything like it.
我听过 在圣所听见的
I have, on Sanctuary.
你现在信他了
You believe him now?
退下
Stand down!
让你队员把武器放下 士官长
Tell your team to lower their weapons, Master Chief.
这什么意思
What is this?
-士官长  -立刻
- Chief? - Now.
我都描述不出来你们处境有多糟糕
I can't even describe the amount of shit you're in.
我都描述不出来
I can't even describe
你的脸会发生什么事
what's about to happen to your face.
这帮人谁啊
Who the hell are these people?
我有舰队指挥部的头号命令
I carry priority orders from FLEETCOM.
－什么命令－将你们带回
- What orders? - To bring you in.
你妨碍了我的任务 让开
You are impeding my mission, move.
没有任务
There is no mission.
－你偷了一架兀鹰－什么
- You stole a Condor. - What?
－伪造飞行计划－她说什么呢
- Falsified a flight plan. - What is she talking about?
你现在都不允许穿战斗装备
You're not even authorized to be in those suits right now,
更别提拿枪指着我的脸了
let alone pointing a gun at my face.
所以退下 否则我们就动手了
So stand down, or we will engage you.
那祝你们好运
Good luck with that.
士官长 我们该怎么办
Chief, what do we do?
钴队呢
Where is Cobalt Team?
－最后机会－约翰
- Last chance. - John.
告诉我钴队在哪 要不然我就进去了
Tell me where Cobalt is, or I'm going through that door.
我是来给你下命令的
I gave you an order.
怎么办
What's the call?
士官长
Chief?
退下 不许开火
Ah, stand down, do not fire!
－士官长－他们来过
- Chief. - They were here.
我可以证明
I can prove it.
不是这样证明的
Not like this.
我们在一千英尺高的地方
We were a thousand feet up,
风在呼啸 电缆嘎吱作响
wind whipping, cables groaning.
那里的温度不超过2度
Couldn't have been more than two degrees up there.
- 一月 懂的吧  －嗯
- January, you know? - Yeah.
我撑不住了
And I can't hold it anymore.
我被绑在安全带上 往下看
I'm strapped in the harness, and I look down,
告诉亚瑟 说"我得释放一下"
I tell Arthur, I say, "I gotta go."
他该怎么办
What's he gonna do?
你尿在亚瑟叔叔身上了
You peed on Uncle Arthur?
尿他身上了 他能怎么办
I peed on him. What could he do?
好 抬下巴
Okay, lift your chin up, yeah.
你怎么了
What the hell's wrong with you?
这故事很好笑呀
This shit is funny.
可我以前听过
Well, I've heard it before.
那又有什么区别
What difference does that make?
我重复讲的时候你就应该笑
You're supposed to damn well laugh when I repeat myself.
老糊涂的人是我
I'm the one that's senile.
都不知道你在抱怨什么
I don't know what you're complaining about.
我没在抱怨
I'm not complaining.
你想抱怨来着
Well, I mean, you want to.
怎么了
What is it?
我会替你保密的
Your secret's safe with me.
是跟那件
Is this about that thing
你不该告诉我的事有关吗
that you weren't supposed to tell me?
你不该记得的
You weren't supposed to remember.
记得什么又不是我能选的
I don't choose what I forget.
我可能得走了
I might have to go away.
去哪儿
Where?
我没法带你一起走
And I can't take you with me.
- 我知道－我想带的可是没法带
- I know. - I want to, but I can't.
看到那座桥了吗
You see that bridge?
我阻止不了 爸
I can't stop it, Dad.
你知道那座桥是谁建的不
You know who built that bridge?
不是我说了算的
It's not up to me.
- 太迟了－我建的
- It's too late. - I built that bridge.
我和你亚瑟叔叔
Me and your Uncle Arthur.
竣工那天
The day it was finished,
我和你妈 你姐姐一起踏上了那座桥
I walked across it with your mum, and your sister.
她那会儿还不到13岁
She couldn't have been more than three.
牵着她的小手
Held her little hand.
她不让我抱
She wouldn't let me pick her up.
想一路走完全程
She wanted to walk the whole way.
是的
Yeah.
好吧
All right.
她什么时候来啊
So when's she coming?
你姐
Your sister.
她走了 爸
She's gone, Dad.
朱莉娅走了
Julia's gone.
妈也是
Mum, too.
哦
Oh.
- 就剩你跟我了－我知道
- It's just you and me. - I know that.
我当然知道了
I damn well know that.
别以为我不知道
Don't think that I don't know that.
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
没事
It's okay.
抱歉 我只是 对不起 有时候我脑子会糊涂
Sorry, I just, sorry, I just get confused sometimes.
没事的
It's okay.
不代表我不知道什么是真实的
Doesn't mean that I don't know what's real.
明天见  好吗
See you tomorrow, okay?
好
Okay.
- 保证   －我保证
- Promise me... - Yeah, I promise.
不是 答应我别让他们把我活捉
No, promise me you won't let them take me alive.
擅离职守
Absent without leave,
未经授权使用武器系统
unauthorized deployment of weapons systems,
违反
violation of,
你们管偷一架该死的兀鹰叫什么
I mean, what do you even call stealing a goddamn Condor?
长官
Sir.
你这违反了15项《军队统一法典》的规定
I'm looking at 15 infractions of the UCMJ,
其中一项涉及将上膛的武器
one of which involves pointing a loaded weapon
指着军官的脸
in the face of an officer?
是我干的 长官
I did that, sir.
长官 我有可靠消息
Sir, I had credible information.
你那是感觉 是妄想
You had a feeling. You had a delusion.
你越界了
You went outside the chain.
对不对
Didn't ya?
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
立即生效
Effective immediately,
银队暂停作战
Silver Team is suspended from combat operations,
直到另行通知
'til further notice.
凯斯上将 我知道
Admiral Keyes, I know--
你知道个屁 因为你就不该知道
You know nothing because it's not your job to know.
那是我的事
It's mine.
你的工作就是服从命令
Your job is to follow orders.
钴队到过韦谢格勒 长官
Cobalt was at Visegrád, sir.
那是什么
What's that?
四天前 钴队被派往阿克蒂斯四号
Four days ago, Cobalt was deployed to Aktis IV.
不 不是的
No, this isn't right.
我看过钴队飞行计划
I saw Cobalt's flight plan.
－士官长－我看到了
- Chief. - I saw it.
他们给篡改了
They changed it!
我清楚自己看到了什么
I know what I saw.
约翰-117被解除现役
John-117 is relieved from active duty,
在通过精神评估之前
and will be confined to barracks
不得离开营房
'til such a time as he clears a psychiatric evaluation.
什么
A what?
117将接受精神化学检查
117 will submit to neurochemical--
是你的命令 还是阿克森的
Is this you, or is this Ackerson?
约翰 别说了
John, stop.
整理服装 解散
Rack your suits, dismissed.
你有试过为我们辩护吗
Did you even try to defend us?
我是你不用面对军事法庭审判的唯一原因
I'm the only reason you're not facing a court-martial.
你骗我们
You lied to us.
我把完成任务需要知道的事都告诉你们了
I told you what you needed to know to complete the mission.
－根本没有任务－钴队就在韦谢格勒
- There was no mission. - Cobalt was at Visegrád.
－士官长 能谈谈吗－是海军情报局干的 这一切
- Chief, can I talk to you? - This is ONI, all of it.
－是阿克森干的－不是吧 士官长
- This is Ackerson. - Come on, Chief.
－不然他干嘛来这－听不下去了
- Why do you think he's here? - I can't listen to this.
你们要去哪儿
Where do you think you're going?
瓦纳克
Vannak!
－你失控了－什么
- You are out of control. - What?
你脑子不清楚 反复无常
You're not thinking straight, you're erratic.
你什么时候也开始质疑我的判断了
Since when do you question my judgment?
自从你开始看见死人开始
Since you started seeing dead people.
你在圣所看见马吉这事我谁都没告诉
I didn't tell anyone you said you saw Makee on Sanctuary.
约翰 我想帮你
John, I'm trying to help you.
我想以朋友身份跟你谈谈
I'm trying to talk to you, as your friend.
我用不着朋友 下士 我要的是斯巴达战士
I don't need a friend, Petty Officer, I need a Spartan.
你为什么不试着当个称职的战士呢
Why don't you try doing that?
125 你不能解散
125, you are not dismissed!
嘿
Hey!
她是谁啊
Who is she?
-关  -嘘
- Kwan? - Shh!
你干什么
What're you doing?
－你有危险－我看得出来
- You're in danger. - I can see that.
不   是鲁比·安要动你
Not from Ruby Ann.
我是说你们的船员
I'm talking about your crew.
鲁比·安把他们买通了
Ruby Ann bought them off.
－他们摆脱了索伦－什么
- They got rid of Soren. - What?
－接下来就是你－什么
- You're next. - What?
索伦是不是－我不知道
- Is Soren-- - I don't know.
你赶紧带上凯斯勒走
You have to get Kessler and go.
－拜托 我干掉你了哎－才没有
- Come on, man, I got you. - Did not.
开玩笑吗 这个距离
Are you kidding me, at this range?
- 拜托 兄弟－这是士官长
- Come on, man. - It's Master Chief.
是啊  是士官长
Yeah, it's Master Chief,
大卸八块了嘛
in eight different pieces.
才不是 你打偏了
Nope, nope, you missed.
好吧
Fine.
你们干嘛呢
What are you doing here?
玩呀
Playing.
我们有好消息
We have good news.
飞船修好了
Ship's fixed.
我们可以出发了
We can leave.
你之前说要几天时间的
You said it would take a couple of days.
那可是索伦
It's Soren.
－我们加班干了整宿  －过来
- We worked all night. - Come here.
－没玩儿完呢   －凯斯勒
- We're not finished. - Kessler.
该走了
Time to go.
我能去吗
Can I come?
－好呀  －不行
- Yeah. - No.
所有人都去
Everybody goes.
我们是一家人嘛
We're all family.
你们先过去 我一会儿去飞船跟你们汇合
You go ahead, I'll meet you at the ship.
我们可以等
We can wait.
不必麻烦 我能行的
Don't trouble yourselves, I can manage.
－卡丽娜  －不麻烦
- Carina. - It's no trouble.
卡丽娜
Carina.
走了
Come on.
去拿你东西
Get your things.
关 你可以出来了
Kwan, you can come out.
你们当初加入海军情报局的时候 就想干这事吗
So, when you guys joined ONI, is this what you had in mind?
我们也不喜欢这样 士官长
We don't like this any more than you do, Chief.
如果你们再靠近点
If you get any closer,
我们就得谈谈此刻的感觉了
we're gonna have to talk about our feelings.
就是例行的心理评估 士官长
It's just a routine psych eval, Chief.
－抱歉－什么
- Sorry. - What?
－嗨－嘿 里兹
- Hi. - Hey, Riz.
他们把我们的训练取消了
They canceled our training.
我干坐在铺位上 然后就
I was sitting in my bunk, so--
就决定过来
So you decided to come by here?
是的
Yeah.
看看我发现谁了
Look who I found.
嘿 一起吃晚饭呀
Hey, join us for dinner.
约会之夜泡汤了
There goes date night.
不好意思啊
Oh, I'm sorry.
不会不会 别听他的
No, no, no, no, don't listen to him.
他对约会之夜的想法就是他听着
His idea of date night ends with him falling asleep
卫星信号入睡 而我则去洗碗
listening to the sat-link, and me doing the dishes.
宝儿 不是你洗碗 是机器洗
Babe, you don't do the dishes, the machine does.
总得有人按按钮吧 过来
Someone has to press the button, come here.
希望你饿了
You know, I hope you're hungry.
吃完饭我给你治疗一下吧
I can give you some treatment after we eat, yeah?
我来不是治疗的
Oh, I didn't really come here for that.
没事吧
Everything okay?
我觉得我刚开始走
Um, I guess I just started walking,
结果发现不知道去哪儿
but it turns out I don't really have anywhere to go.
真服了 你让我好难过 泣就旦土土
Oh, for God's sake, you're making me sad.
我们必须得喝一杯了 坐
Now we have to drink, sit.
看起来好漂亮
It looks beautiful.
谢谢
Thank you.
路易斯身体可好
Louis' health?
喝的这是什么
What are we drinking?
你最喜欢的
Your favorite.
聊聊吧
Talk to me.
前几天 你说
The other day, you said
还有其他的生活方式 其他事可以做
there were other ways to live, other things to be.
没错
That's right.
比如说
Like what?
我们不知道任务未经授权
We didn't know the mission wasn't authorized.
我 里兹 瓦纳克
Me, Riz, Vannak.
一无所知
We were in the dark.
顺便说一句
And for the record,
士官长只是在做他认为正确的事
Chief was just doing what he thought was right.
这正是我担心的
Well, that's what concerns me.
很感谢你过来
Look, I appreciate you coming down here
为你的指挥官辩护
to advocate for your CO.
如果士官长越界
If the Chief went outside the chain,
就需要纪律约束 我明白
there needs to be discipline, I get that.
但我们的存在不是跟这儿干坐着
But we're not built to sit around and wait.
这对我们不好
It's not good for us.
我们要进入战斗
We need to be in the fight.
我不会改变决定的
I'm not gonna change my decision.
我不是让你改
I'm not asking you to.
现在正处于战时 长官
We are at war, sir.
我们仍然是你最好的武器
We're still the best weapons you have.
你是建议我在没有队长的情况下
Are you suggesting I deploy Silver Team
给银队部署任务吗
without its leader?
不是  长官
No, sir.
就我一个
Just me.
暂时的 直到约翰没问题
Temporarily, 'til John's cleared.
如果有问题呢
And if he's not?
他可是士官长啊
He's the Chief.
20分钟前
Twenty minutes ago,
约翰打晕了负责监视他的士兵
John incapacitated the soldiers assigned to monitor him,
然后逃离此处
and escaped this facility.
什么
What?
他告诉你他的计划了吗
Did he share his plans with you?
计划 什么啊
Plans, what?
－什么计划－他在哪儿
- What plans? - Where is he?
我不知道
Oh, I don't know.
上次我们谈话
Last time we spoke,
我问过你是否担心约翰的
I asked you if you had concerns
精神稳定性 你说
about John's mental stability, and you said---
－那是之前－什么之前
- That was before. - Before what?
这样多久了
How long has this been going on?
－我不知道－是科塔娜被移除后
- I don't know. - Since Cortana was removed,
还是约翰跟星盟特工接触过之后
or since John interacted with the Covenant agent?
我看过档案
I reviewed the file.
你在暗示什么
What are you implying?
你我都清楚他已经失常了
You and I both know he's not himself.
凯 我想跟你说件事
Look, Kai, I, I want to share something with you,
不是以你上司身份告诉你
and this isn't me speaking as your superior, this is...
有时候人是不会好转的
Sometimes people don't get better.
他只是需要时间
He just needs time.
有时候 坚持会造成更大的伤害
Sometimes, we do more damage by holding on.
我不能留下来看着他
I can't stay and watch him.
我知道
I know.
告诉我该怎么做
Tell me what to do.
有时候需要几周才能来这里 有时候要几个月
Sometimes it takes weeks to get here, sometimes months.
有些人根本就能撑到抵达
Some never get here at all.
我们离开了牧歌星时是四艘飞船
We left Madrigal with four ships.
到的时候只剩一艘了
We arrived with one.
看到那个了吗
You see that?
签订通行证之前 他们会把你安置在那里
That's where they process you before you're indentured.
可不是免费的
It's not free.
就没有免费的东西
Nothing is free.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
对于你所经历的遭遇
For what happened to you.
别这样
Don't be.
大多数人更惨
Most people have it worse,
有时候我觉得自己活该
and sometimes I think I deserve it.
这是对我的惩罚
I'm being punished.
－别这么说－这是事实
- Don't talk like that. - It's true.
我不该在这里的 这不是我的生活
I'm not supposed to be here, this isn't my life.
我没能履行对我的人民和星球的责任
I failed my responsibility to my people and my planet.
你不能因此责怪自己
You can't blame yourself for that.
我是关哈
I'm Kwan Ha.
我家族世代
My family protected Madrigal
都在保护牧歌星
for more generations than anyone can count.
等轮到我的时候
And when it was my turn...
关
Kwan?
该走了 我们可以混进去
It's time to go. We can blend in.
得立即行动
We have to move now.
脱了 他们会注意到你的
Take it off, they'll notice you.
－是要躲起来吗－不是
- Are we hiding? - No.
－我们要去哪儿－去找你爸爸回来
- Where are we going? - To get your dad back.
要害怕吗
Are we scared?
不 跟紧
No. Stay close.
把头低下
Keep your head down.
别看
Don't look.
赶紧往前走
Rising forward.
继续走
Keep moving!
－现在要害怕吗－系好安全带
- Are we scared now? - Strap in.
一切都会没事的 凯斯
Everything's gonna be okay, Kes.
我们现在就去找你爸爸
We're gonna get your dad now.
都跟你说了
Told you.
哦 不  不
Oh, no, no.
不 我们不会成功的
No, we're not gonna make it!
稳住
Hold on!
妈妈
Mom!
糟糕
Damn it!
你干什么啊
What are you doing?
等我行动 然后带凯斯勒离开这里
Wait for my move, then get Kessler out of here.
－走舱门－你呢
- Use the hatch. - What about you?
能把你俩送上
It's worth enough to get both of you
－那艘运输船就够了   －不
- on that transport. - No.
答应我你会把他带上那艘船
Promise me you'll get him on that ship.
答应我你会保护他
Promise me you'll protect him.
拉埃拉
Laera!
－不行 他们会杀了你的－妈妈
- No, they'll kill you. - Mom?
打开 拉埃拉
Open up, Laera!
过会儿见
I'll see you soon.
别逼我把这门烧了啊
Don't make me torch this door.
她出来了
There she is.
很识相 要不然有可能大家都不好看
Smart girl, this could have got messy.
－拉埃拉 抱歉 我从没－得了吧 不是针对你
- Laera, I'm sorry, I never-- - Give it up, it's not personal.
就是
It is!
我们在中继站80米外
We found Cobalt Team 80 meters
发现了钴队踪迹
from the relay.
他们在树上
They were in the trees.
我们在该区域观察到等离子武器留下的痕迹
We observed plasma scarring in the area.
应该是打了他们一个措手不及
I don't think they saw it coming.
谢谢  队长
Thank you, Captain.
你打算怎么处理
How would you like to handle this?
这些尸体 长官
The bodies, sir?
没有尸体
There are no bodies.
－列为失踪吧－收到
- I would list it as MIA. - Sir.
走了
Let's go.
你还好吧 上将
You all right, Admiral?
不好
No.
我理解
I understand.
这是场悲剧
It's a tragedy.
－你知道吗－你说什么
- Did you know... - Pardon me?
你把我们的士兵送进敌营的时候
Did you know that Master Chief's suspicions were valid
知道士官长的怀疑是正确的吗
when you sent our soldiers out into a hostile--
我不喜欢你的言下之意
I resent the implication.
我想知道你知道什么
I want to know what you knew,
还想知道你什么时候知道的
and I want to know when you knew it.
－冷静一下－冷静
- Just calm down. - Calm down?
星盟就在这个星球上
The Covenant is on this planet!
不过是时间问题
It was a matter of time.
这一天总要来的
This day was inevitable.
这是个数学问题 上将
It's mathematics, Admiral.
每次分析 每次模拟
In every analysis, every simulation--
这他妈不是什么该死的模拟
This is not a goddamn simulation!
是 是不是
Right, it's not.
但我的工作是决定下一步该怎么走
But it's my job to decide what to do next.
我们必须向指挥部发出警报
We have to alert command.
我跟你保证 你上级已经知道了
I assure you, your superiors are already fully aware.
我们要启动冬季应急计划
We need to initiate the Winter Contingency.
立即开始疏散平民
Begin immediate civilian evacuation!
结束了 上将 这次我们赢不了的
It's over, Admiral. We don't get to win this one.
如果你发出疏散警报
If you send out an evacuation alert,
就会陷入混乱 恐慌
we'll have chaos, panic.
星盟部队几天前袭击了钴队
The Covenant element hit Cobalt Team days ago.
我们只能假设星盟舰队就在不远处
We can only assume the Covenant fleet isn't far behind.
计划是有的
There is a plan in place,
但要做出些艰难的抉择
but it's going to require some hard choices.
我要知道你是站在我这边的
I need to know that you're with me.
－我们不战斗了－我没这么说
- We're not gonna fight. - I didn't say that.
我们会战斗 只是不会赢
We're going to fight, we're just not going to win.
－这里是致远星－我知道
- This is Reach. - I know.
数百万人的家园
Home to millions of people--
我们会尽力挽救
And we will save what we can.
－这里是我的家－也是我的
- This is my home! - It is my home too!
别以为这不会让我付出所有
Don't think for a second this doesn't cost me everything.
但这是现实 上将
but this is reality, Admiral.
我们要么面对 要么死
We can either face it or we die.
我们说话这会儿 重要资产
Essential assets are being transported
已经被运出星球了
off the planet as we speak.
去收拾东西吧
Get your things together.
不要告诉任何人
Tell no one.
我不会逃跑的
I won't run.
等我们能赢的那天你再去打仗
You'll fight another day when we can win.
凯斯上将 我能指望你吗
Admiral Keyes, can I count on you?
去你妈的吧
Go fuck yourself.
我丈夫呢
Where's my husband?
－他还活着吗－安塔雷斯
- Is he alive? - Antares?
还不算迟 安塔雷斯－已经迟了
- It's not too late, Antares. - Yeah, it is.
继续  关
Go on, Kwan.
停下
Halt.
等等
Wait.
我妈妈呢
Where's my mom?
我一会儿能见到她吗
Will I see her soon?
跟我说实话
Tell the truth.
能的
Yes.
－城里最棒的 来点不－不了
- Best in the city. You want? - No.
－试试－不了 谢谢
- Try it. - No, thank you.
你一直都有这方面问题
You've always had this problem.
你掌控不了
You are not in control.
你是说不听指挥
You mean not controllable.
我们有过协议
We had an agreement.
你要给我带来的是信息 而不是关注度
You were to bring me information, not attention.
我有消息
I have information.
但我想先知道你打算用它做什么
But I wanna know what you're gonna do with it first.
我们有共同目标 就是赢得战争
We have a common goal to win the war.
别误把我当朋友对待了
Don't mistake me for a friend.
好吧
Okay.
我认为星盟在这里
I believe the Covenant is here.
－在拉面里－在致远星上
- In the ramen? - On Reach.
你认真的
You're serious.
队斯巴达战士失踪了
A team of Spartans went missing.
舰队指挥部假装不知道发生了什么
FLEETCOM is pretending they don't know what happened.
你觉得是星盟
And do you think it's the Covenant that--
就是星盟
I know it's the Covenant.
我建议你考虑清楚自己说的话
I suggest you consider what you're saying.
这就是我一直在做的
That's all I've been doing.
我一直在想这事 一直在说
I've been thinking it. I've been saying it.
可没人往心里去
And nobody seems to be listening.
－海军情报局知道的－小声点
- ONI knows! - Keep your voice down.
海军情报局知道的 他们把真相掩盖起来了
ONI knows. They're covering it up.
他们为什么要这么做
Why would they do that?
海军情报局要保护自己
The ONI protects itself.
跟他们树敌
Make them your enemy,
即便你是士官长
and it won't matter that you're Master Chief,
也都不再有用
you will cease to be useful.
你一旦不再有用 那么
And when you cease to be useful, that--
－不是 你没明白－你为什么要战斗 约翰
- No, you're not listening, - Why do you fight, John?
－什么－你战斗 为什么
- What? - You fight, why?
为了要赢 要保卫我们的家园
To win, to defend our home.
要保护人类
To preserve humanity.
错 你战斗是因为我让你去战斗
No, you fight because I tell you to.
你是个战士 就当好一名战士
You are a soldier, be a soldier.
这就是你要做的
This is what you will do.
回去吧
Go back there.
回去舰队指挥部
Go back to FLEETCOM.
该拍谁马屁就拍谁马屁
Kiss whatever ass you have to kiss.
去禁闭室服刑
You go do your time in the brig.
微笑
Smile.
再也不许提这事
You'll never speak of it again.
他们可能会再授予你枚奖章
They will probably give you another medal.
我要知道我们都理解对方意思了
I need to know we understand each other.
你什么时候离开海军情报局的 上将
When exactly did you leave ONI, Admiral?
如果你从这里走出去 那我就帮不了你了
If you walk out of here, I won't be able to help you.
－你就没离开过－别反抗了 约翰
- You never left. - Stand down, John.
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
我从来不知道他们其实那么脆弱
I never understood how fragile they really are.
脆弱
Fragile?
是啊 因为你让他们变成那样的
Yes, because you made them that way.
不
No.
他们还是孩子的时候你就把他们带走训练他们
You took them when they were children.
训练他们
You conditioned them.
等他们长大 可以独立思考的时候
And then when they were old enough to think for themselves,
你就确保他们永远不会去独立思考
you made sure they never would.
你把这些植入物放进去
You put in those pellets.
他们就再也感受不到欲望
So they never had to feel desire
野心或者偏好
or ambition or preference.
这样他们就不会选择除你之外的人了
So they would never choose anyone other than you.
就是这样 对吧
And that's it, isn't it?
- 你来干嘛的     －来跟你道别
- Why are you here? - I just came to say goodbye.
我要走了
I'm leaving.
还有我 我应该是想让你知道
And I, I suppose I wanted you to know
你的努力没有白费 凯瑟琳
that your efforts weren't in vain, Catherine,
尽管你看不到那一天
you won't be here to see it.
但你创造出来的东西 虽然可能破碎不堪
But these things that you made, broken as they may be,
但会成为某种
they're going to become the foundation
非凡事物的基
for something extraordinary.
我希望这最终能给你一些安慰
And I hope that gives you some comfort in the end.
你难道不想知道她是怎么死的吗
Don't you want to know how she died?
什么
What?
朱莉娅 你以为我不知道她是谁吗
Julia. Did you think I didn't know who she was?
他们所有人我都记得
I remember all of them.
尤其是你姐姐
Especially your sister.
她 好奇心很重
She was... she was so curious.
问过很多问题
She used to ask so many questions.
但你永远不知道谁能挺过
But you never know who's going to make it through
增强手术 谁挺不过来
the augmentation and who isn't.
她没挺过来
And she didn't.
对
No.
她快死了
She was dying.
她不清楚原因 理解不了
She didn't know why. She couldn't understand.
我跟她说了你刚跟我说的类似的话
I told her more or less what you just told me.
就是即便她看不到
That even though she wouldn't see it,
也会是接下来前进的一小部分
she would be this small part of the next step forward.
不知道她听懂没
I don't know if she understood.
她很害怕
She was so scared.
但我知道她非常爱你
But I do know that she loved you very much.
希望这能给你一些安慰
And I hope that gives you some comfort.
是的
Yeah.
你不是要走了么
I thought you were leaving.
我不想留你一个人
I didn't want you to be alone.
我不是怪物
I'm not a monster.
二位重新认识一下吧
I'll let you two get reacquainted.
你这样我很难帮你啊
You are making it very difficult for me to help you.
- 老大 我们要退出跃迁空间了－听到了
- Boss, we're exiting slip space. - I heard you.
要是我不拦着他们
I let them have their way...
你早就死了
...you'd already be dead.
我们对你很好 安塔雷斯
We were good to you, Antares.
这个嘛
Oh. Well.
谢谢你让我勉强度日
Thank you for allowing me to barely exist
跟这帮傻瓜平分一份微薄的
and to scrape out a meager living split four ways
生活费 而你和你丈夫却把牧歌星的钱
with these bozos while you and your husband spent
- 都花在－你在说什么
- all that Madrigal money on-- - What are you talking about?
别装傻了
Don't play stupid!
我知道你不傻
I know you're not.
我一般都可以跟我丈夫讲道理
I can usually reason with my husband,
但要让他知道这事
but when he finds out about this--
我不是很担心 我最后一次见到索伦
I'm not really worried. Last I see Soren,
他正在一艘开往致远星的囚舰上呢
his was on a prison ship headed for Reach.
所以踏实点吧
So settle in.
得有阵子了
It could be a while.
－你个王八蛋     －错 我是机会主义者
- You're a son of a bitch. - No, I'm an opportunist.
东西呢
Now, where is it?
谁去看一下怎么回事
Would somebody please deal with that?
我被吵的都没法想事情了
I can't hear myself think.
谢谢
Thank you.
我不知道鲁比·安答应过你什么
I don't know what Ruby Ann promised you,
但你被耍了 安塔雷斯 现在还不算晚
but you are getting played, Antares, and it's not too late.
拜托别说了
Stop, please.
索伦什么都会跟你说
Soren tells you everything.
你知道他把东西藏哪儿了
You know where he's stashed it.
－藏什么－宝藏
- Stashed what? - The treasure.
你觉得很好笑是吗
You think this is funny?
我向你保证
Because I guarantee you...
并不是哦
...it's not.
你所说的宝藏就是一个装满
What you call a treasure was a box full
本来就不值多少钱的氘币的箱子
of deuterium tokens that wasn't worth much to begin with.
够了
Heard enough.
鲁比·安不想要钱
Ruby Ann doesn't want the money.
她想要碎石星
She wants The Rubble.
冷静
Calm down.
何必要逼我呢
Why are you making me do this?
你以为我想让凯斯勒当孤儿吗
You think I want to leave Kessler an orphan?
我很喜欢那孩子的
I love that kid.
她在嘲笑你
She's laughing at you.
- 听到那个声音了吗－听到了
- You hear that sound? - Yeah.
嗯 你觉得是不是该做点什么
Yeah, you think you should do something about it?
我在盯着她呀
I'm watching.
去看看那是什么声音
Go see what's making that sound.
－藏哪儿了－她在拖延时间
- Where's the stash? - She's stalling.
能闭嘴不
Would you shut up?
我不记得有问过任何人意见
I don't remember asking anyone's opinion.
我是舰长
I'm the captain.
这是我的飞船
This is my ship,
这是你最后一次机会 拉埃拉
and this is your last chance, Laera.
东西在哪儿
Where is it?
我告诉不了你 因为根本就不存在
I can't tell you because it doesn't exist.
而且就算真存在 我也不会告诉你的
And if it did exist, I wouldn't tell you.
你刚浪费了最后一次机会
You've just taken it outta my hands.
记住 我也不想出现接下来发生的事的
Just remember, I didn't want what happens next.
你有一分钟时间重新考虑你的立场
You have one minute to rethink your position.
没必要走到这步的
It doesn't have to be this way.
想想凯斯勒
Think of Kessler!
索伦在致远星 谁来照顾他
With Soren on Reach, who's gonna look after him?
告诉我我想知道的
Just tell me what I wanna kn--
凯斯勒呢
Where's Kessler?
关
Kwan?
关 我在问你问题
Kwan, I asked you a question--
－我把他送上运输船了   －我告诉过你跟他待在一起的
- I put him on the transport. - I told you to stay with him.
－我办不到－为什么不行
- I couldn't. - Why not?
因为那样你就死定了
'Cause then you'd be dead.
我要跟佩雷斯下士谈谈
I need to speak with Corporal Perez.
－她不在－她在哪儿
- She's not here. - Where is she?
她是个好姑娘
She's a good girl.
是的  女士
Yes, ma'am.
但我认为恶魔在跟着你
But I think the devil follows you.
几点了
What time is it?
很晚了
- Late. - Uh-huh.
我怎么会在这里
What am I doing here?
你还记得我们聊过什么吗
Do you remember what we talked about?
你让我
You asked me to...
别让他们活捉我
To don't let them take me alive?
是 是的
Yeah, that's right.
就是今天了
Today's the day?
Today's the day.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
呕
Ohh.
有人来看你了 爸
There's someone here to see you, Dad.
朱莉娅
Oh, Julia.
Julia.
佩雷斯下士
Corporal Perez.
从没进过教堂吧
Never been in a church before, have you?
嗯
Mnh-mnh.
人们来这里寻求安慰
People come here for comfort.
寻求保护
For protection.
寻求答案
For answers.
他们如愿了吗
Do they find them?
有时候可以
Sometimes.
你呢
Do you?
在圣所的时候
On Sanctuary,
星盟出现之前我
before the Covenant came, I...
我在雾里 看到些东西
I saw something... in the fog.
你是说那个女人
You mean the woman?
她是真实存在的对不对
She's real, isn't she?
是的
Yes.
我睡不着
I don't sleep.
脑子里一直响着那个声音
I can't get that sound outta my head.
这是在圣所的录音
This is a recording from Sanctuary.
不止是段干扰
It's not just interference.
不止是个声音
Not just a sound.
里面有别的东西
There's something underneath.
是什么
What is it?
一段祷文
A prayer.
我给予你们祝福 致远星的人们
I bring you blessings, people of Reach.
要知道我来时无有慈悲
Know that I've come without mercy.
无有怜悯
Without pity.
要知道我是你们灭亡的工具
Know that I am the instrument of your extinction.
我将此星球献为燔祭
I bring this planet forth as a burnt offering.
于这祭坛上 我放上恶魔的头颅
Upon this altar, I place the head of the Demon.
愿他的鲜血引领通往光晕环的道路
May his blood mark the way to the Sacred Ring
祝圣我的人民伟大的旅程
and consecrate the Great Journey of my people.
要知道我是瓦尔加塔奈
Know that I am Var 'Gatanai.
要知道我是 死神
Know that I am... Death.
他们已经来了
They're already here...
对不对
Aren't they?